<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<document-metadata version="1.0" xmlns="http://breeze.macromedia.com/">
	<document-info>
		<title>Linked In How To</title>
		<summary></summary>
		<author/>
		<keywords/>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000001.jpg"/>
		<view-link href="/Viewer.swf?slide={position}"/>
	</document-info>
	<section type="slide" position="1" xmlns="">
		<title>LinkedIn:  Network &amp; Job Search</title>
		<content>LinkedIn: 
Network &amp; Job Search Auburn UniversityCareer Development Services303 Martin Hall334.844.4744www.auburn.edu/career </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000001.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="2" xmlns="">
		<title>Why network?</title>
		<content>Why network? It’s the best way to get a jobYou become a human applying rather than a piece of paperThe other optionYour paper or digital resume  is in a “stack” with over 100 other unknown applicants </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000002.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="3" xmlns="">
		<title>Why LinkedIn?</title>
		<content>Why LinkedIn? Members from over 200 countriesExecutives from every Fortune 500 company with profilesOver 400,000 groups Network of 43 million professionalsLinkedIn profiles are often one of the first searches on Google (you will want it to be  professional) </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000003.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="4" xmlns="">
		<title>So…how do I use it?</title>
		<content>So…how do I use it? Develop a complete profile (It’s 40X more likely to be seen)Never include anything you wouldn’t want printed on the cover of the New York Times Tell your story – 1st impressions are criticalHave a strong title and summaryInclude keywords/specialtiesLoad a professional photoInclude volunteer and other activitiesKeep your profile current! </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000004.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="5" xmlns="">
		<title>What else?</title>
		<content>What else? Obtain recommendations (one per position held)Claim your LinkedIn url – add a ‘public profile’Create your profile in additional languages if applicableInclude website links to research or professional blogsUpdate your ‘Opportunity Preferences’ </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000005.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="6" xmlns="">
		<title>Groups, Applications, Blogs, Articles…</title>
		<content>Groups, Applications, Blogs, Articles… Sole purpose of these items is to connect with and assist one anotherApplications allow you to post portions of blog posts you’ve written to your pageAmazon Reading Lists allow visitors to review your current interestsSlide share allows you to share presentations </content>
		<related-content>&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;</related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000006.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="7" xmlns="">
		<title>How to Connect</title>
		<content>How to Connect Determine your interests, skills, and valuesJoin groups that are related to your interests, field, university, etc. Connect with people you already know: family, friends, family friends, professors, former classmates, employers, coworkers, etc.Watch the connections your links make as you may know them as well (Connect but don’t spam!!)Remember that you are not only represent yourself but also Auburn University. Be professional! </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000007.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="8" xmlns="">
		<title>Before you Connect</title>
		<content>Before you Connect Determine what information you are seekingPrepare list of questions and introductory emailBrief introductionWhy you are writing Similar to elevator speech  (tipsheet &amp; website)Find out more about your potential connection and review his/her profileRequest advice/guidance…NOT jobsTrends in their industry/companies they respectHow they prepared themselves to succeed </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000008.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="9" xmlns="">
		<title>How to Maintain Connections</title>
		<content>How to Maintain Connections Request (and give) recommendationsIllustrate achievementsProject credibilityNever share personal information with friends or colleagues unless you have permissionAsk for telephone connection: 15-20 minutesAlways follow-up with thank you emails/notesKeep your contacts/connections informed </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000009.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="10" xmlns="">
		<title>Increase Your Credibility</title>
		<content>Increase Your Credibility ‘Answer’ questions as applicable – if you get a ‘good answer’ mark, you are seen as an expertPost questions that you may have but remember that millions of people have access to what you writeWrite answers/questions in Word and use spell- and grammar-check and then cut and paste into LinkedIn  </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000010.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="11" xmlns="">
		<title>LinkedIn and Job Searching</title>
		<content>LinkedIn and Job Searching Utilize ‘Find a Job’ feature to search for positionsJoin groups and check their ‘Jobs’ tabsWhen you join groups, sign up to receive the ‘feed’Upgrade to a premium account for free if graduating this year: http://grads.linkedin.com  </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000011.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="12" xmlns="">
		<title>Research Companies</title>
		<content>Research Companies Find information on companies in a specific geographic locationLook for related companies and ‘popular’ profilesWhen you find a company you’d like to work for, review ‘before’ and ‘after’ career pathsCheck out a company’s ‘new hires’ and see how similar their profiles are to yours </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000012.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="13" xmlns="">
		<title>How can CDS help?</title>
		<content>How can CDS help? Build an effective resume firstDevelop your Elevator SpeechExplore other networking tools/skillsCareerShift and Tiger Recruiting Link (TRL) @ jobs.auburn.edu </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000013.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="14" xmlns="">
		<title>Questions</title>
		<content>Questions Career Development Services303 Martin Hall334.844.4744www.auburn.edu/career Walk-in Hours:M – F, noon – 4 p.m.Call for an appointment:M – F, 8 a.m. – 4:30 p.m. Resource: http://www.linkedin.com/in/plbsimpson </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000014.jpg"/>
	</section>
</document-metadata>
